Philip Leslie Hale
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Memorial Book, circa 1862-1962, Series 5:; (Boxes 4-6, 8, OV 9; 2.3 linear ft.)
  Research files and catalogs, compiled 1932-1939 by Hale's friend Albert J. Kennedy for a never-published memorial volume, include extensive correspondence and notes of interviews with friends, relatives, colleagues, former students, and models recording their reminiscences of Hale. He collected and organized catalogs of Hale's artwork and exhibitions, along with a variety of other printed material, biographical and genealogical information, and photographs of Hale's work. Many of Kennedy's research notes consist of handwritten transcriptions of published articles by and about Hale. Hale's personal correspondence with Albert J. and Edith Kennedy is filed with Subseries 2.2: General Correspondence.
  Materials concerning interviews by Gertrude Hanna for the proposed book consist of copious notes and some transcripts of direct quotations, with a few letters from interview subjects. She collected reminiscences of Hale from friends, School of MFA, Boston colleagues, and former students, including Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts administrators and faculty members, wife Lilian Westcott Hale, model Marie de Minico, and several former students.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  5.1: Catalog, circa 1887-circa 1934
  5.2: Research Files, circa 1862-1962
  - Catalog, circa 1887-circa 1934, 5.1
    - Card Catalog of the Work of Philip L. Hale with Photographs, undated, (7 folders) (Box 4, Reel unfilmed)
    - Catalogue of Exhibitions in Which Pictures by Philip L. Hale were Shown, undated (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
    - Chronological Catalog of Exhibitions of Lilian W. Hale's Paintings, 1902-1926, circa 1934 (Box 5, Reel D104)
    - Chronological Catalog of Exhibitions of Philip L. Hale's Paintings, 1887-circa 1934, (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel D103)
    - Catalogue of Paintings, etc., with some Photographic Reproductions, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
  - Research Files, circa 1862-1962, 5.2
    - Bibliographic Notes, undated (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
    - Bibliography of the Writings of Edward Everett Hale, undated (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
    - Clippings, 1905-1908, undated, (5 folders) (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
    - Correspondence of Albert J. Kennedy (reminiscences of model Marie de Minico), circa 1932 (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
    - Hale Family Genealogical Notes, undated (Box 5, Reel unfilmed)
    - Correspondence of Albert J. Kennedy, 1932-1939, undated, (5 folders) (Box 5, Reel D103)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Lists, and Notices, 1889-1934, undated (Box 5, Reel D103)
    - Interviews by Gertrude Hanna for Albert J. Kennedy's Proposed Book, 1932-1934, (2 folders) (Box 6, Reel D104)
    - Letters from Gertrude Kennedy to Albert J. Kennedy concerning Interviews, 1934 (Box 6, Reel D104)
    - List of Philip L. Hale's Pictures, A-Z by Title, undated, (see: D103 frames 545-772; 2 folders) (Box 6, Reel D103)
    - Letters from Gertrude Kennedy to Museums, undated (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
    - Lists of Works by Philip L. Hale, 1934, undated (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
    - Notes for a Biography of Philip L. Hale, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
    - Photographs of Works by Philip L. Hale, undated, (7 folders) (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
    - Photographs/Negatives of Works by Philip L. Hale, undated (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
    - Transcripts of Published Articles and Reviews (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
      - Articles about and by Edward Everett Hale, 1883-1908, undated (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
      - Articles about Lilian W. Hale, 1922-1927, undated (Box 6, Reel D104)
      - Articles about Philip L. Hale, sources unknown, undated (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
      - Articles by Philip L. Hale, 1907-1918, undated (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
      - Articles by Philip L. Hale (excerpts), 1888-1921, undated (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
      - Critical Reviews of Philip L. Hale's Work, 1897-1935, undated (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
      - Critical Reviews of Philip L. Hale's Work (excerpts), 1887-1931, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Reel unfilmed)
    - "Art and Artists" and "Art Notes" Columns, Miscellaneous Reviews, and Articles by Philip L. Hale in The Boston Daily Advertiser, 1900-1902 (Box 8 (sol), Reel unfilmed)
    - "Art and Artists" Columns by Philip L. Hale in Boston Commonwealth, 1894-1896 (Box 8 (sol), Reel unfilmed)
    - The Commonwealth, 1862-1962 (Box OV 9, Reel unfilmed)
- Printed Material, circa 1886-1951, Series 6:; (Box 6; 0.25 linear ft.)
  Articles consist of a fragment of "The American Art Association of Paris" published in The Limner, and "For the New Year," from an unidentified newspaper; both are undated.
  Items of note included with the miscellaneous clippings are the entire text of an address delivered by Edward Everett Hale, 1902, and a review mentioning Lilian Westcott Hale's painting exhibited at the National Academy of Design, 1936. Among miscellaneous printed items are covers of The Harvard Lampoon (March 9, 1883) and La comédie parisienne by J. L. Forain designed by Hale, and a prospectus for a book by Hale, Jan Vermeer of Delft. Also of note is "A Christmas Sermon" by Rev. Dr. Edward Everett Hale, inscribed to his son, 1900.
  A small amount of additional printed material is filed with other series. Among Series 3: Writings, is a brochure describing Hale's standard lectures. Series 5: Memorial Book, includes issues of The Commonwealth, 1862-1863, clippings by and about Hale, Hale's "Art Notes" and "Art and Artists" columns published in The Boston Daily Advertiser and Boston Commonwealth, and many handwritten transcripts of published articles about Philip L. and Lilian Westcott Hale.
  - By Hale, "Art in Paris," Columns in Arcadia: A Journal Devoted to Music, Art and Literature, 1892 (Box 6, Reel D102)
  - Articles by Hale, undated (Box 6, Reel D102)
  - By Hale, "Painting and the Plastic Arts," Address delivered on the One Hundredth Anniversary of the Founding of Abbott Academy, 1929 (Box 6, Reel D102)
  - Articles about Philip L. Hale, 1908, 1931 (Box 6, Reel D103)
  - Clippings about Philip L. Hale and his Work, 1895-1951, undated (Box 6, Reel D103)
  - Obituaries, 1932 (Box 6, Reel D103)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1891-1936, undated (Box 6, Reel D102-D103)
  - Miscellaneous Items, 1893-1933 (Box 6, Reel D102-D103)
  - Programs of Concerts and Plays, 1886-1934 (Box 6, Reel D102)
  - Reproductions of Works of Art, undated (Box 6, Reel D104)
- Photographs, circa 1868-1928, Series 7:; (Box 7; 0.4 linear ft.)
  The majority of photographs record works of art, mainly by Philip L. Hale, but also by Lilian Westcott Hale, Robert Payne, and Edmund C. Tarbell.
  Personal photographs include images of Philip L. Hale, relatives, and friends. There are also several group portraits of the Panama-Pacific Exhibition Jury, a group portrait with students, views of Hale at work in his studio and in the classroom, pictures of a summer house, and landscapes (some unidentified and others presumably photographed near the summer house).
  Some printed reproductions from catalogs and periodicals are interfiled with photographs of works of art, and there are also a few among the portraits of Edward Everett Hale and Philip L. Hale. The microfilm identifies these items as photographs.
  A small number of additional photographs are filed among teaching materials that form a part of Series 1: Biographical Information. Series 5: Memorial Book includes a large number of photographs of Hale's art work, and some of the catalogs compiled by Albert J. Kennedy include photographs.
  - Panama-Pacific Exhibition Jury, 1915 (Box 7 (hol), Reel D104)
  - Personal, circa 1868-1921, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel D104)
  - Personal, 1925-1928, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel unfilmed)
  - Works of Art (Box 7 (hol), Reel D104)
    - By Lilian Westcott Hale, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel D104)
    - By Philip L. Hale, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7 (hol), Reel D104)
    - By Philip L. Hale (duplicates), undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel unfilmed)
    - By Robert Payne, 1911 (Box 7 (hol), Reel unfilmed)
    - By Edmund C. Tarbell, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel D104)
  - Unidentified Landscapes, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel D104)